PERSONAL INFORMATION

Ejiro Elum

Lindemann Str 58, 40237 Düsseldorf (Germany)

01639239831

ejelum@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://www.behance.net/gallery/101728561/234xpert-App

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ejiro-elum-b65ab42/

SUMMARY

Environmental scientist; UX/UI designer/frontend developer with deep skills in research methodologies and analytics. Having a vast knowledge in R&D protocols in a team setting in the life sciences, innovative problem solving, and product conceptualization for more than a decade looking for a role in a creative agency in Germany to create user-focused UX experience.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

02/2020-09/2020

Certified UX Designer/Frontend for UX Designers (Career Foundry)

Skills: User -Centred Design, User Research (Competitor Analysis, User Interviews, Data Analysis), Information Architecture and User Flows, Iterative Wireframing and Prototyping Usability and Preference Testing, Style Guides, HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Tools: Adobe CC, Balsamiq, Usability Hub, Canvas

01/2020 - 08/2020

Introduction to UX Design (Certificate)

04/2016-10/2019

Masters - Environmental Science

Universität Trier, Trier (Germany)

Thesis Title

"Partial Lignin Degradation and Phenolic Monomers Formation in Enzymatically Pre-treated Sawdust" Extracted crude laccase enzyme from Trametes versicolor that was used for delignification studies using HPLC.

02/2011-05/2013

Masters Environmental Control and Management

Obafemi Awolowo University, Osun State, Nigeria, Ile-Ife (Nigeria)

Thesis Title

"Bioremediation of a Crude Oil Polluted Soil with the Compost of Cultivated Mushroom (Pleurotus pulmonarius) and Glomus mosseae using Amaranthus hybridus as a Test Plant"

02/1999-12/2006

Bachelor of Science-Microbiology

Obafemi Awolowo University, Osun State, Nigeria, Ile-Ife (Nigeria)

Thesis Title

"Fungal Spore Density in Selected Areas of Modakeke, Ile-Ife Osun State, Nigeria"

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/02/2014-30/12/2015

Logistics Officer/HSE Advisor

Learningate Consulting Ltd, Thomas Estate,, Ajah, Lagos (Nigeria)

- Ensured HSE Compliance in project proposals
- Coordinated logistics during company program/training

04/2010-04/2013

Principal Researcher of the mushroom unit, Crop Production/Protection Dept. OAU, Ile-Ife

Crop Production/Protection Dept. OAU, Ile-Ife, Ile-Ife (Nigeria)

- Setting up of the mushroom cultivation Unit
- Design of Experiments on the growth of Pleurotus Species on different Agricultural substrates
- Practical supervision of thesis for the final year students in Department of Crop Production/Protection Dept. OAU, Ile-Ife

03/2010-04/2010

Team Leader (Social-Economic Impact Assessment study of NDDC Sponsored Projects in Edo State, Nigeria)

DSI Integrated Services Limited, Portharcourt (Nigeria)

- Coordination and deployment of field workers to respective positions
- Collection and processing of GPS data from GPS device with computer

LANGUAGES

English (fluent)

German (A2)

ORGANIZATIONAL ROLES

Team Leader (Social-Economic Impact Assessment study of NDDC sponsored projects in Edo State, Nigeria) (March 2010).

Coordinated 14 persons(University graduates) assigned to work in my team

Head of Final Year Project Students (July 2005 - April 2006)

- Coordinated laboratory activities of 10 project students under the guidance of a supervisor at undergraduate level
- Assisted project students with the procedures for fungi isolation, culturing and identification and gave progress report of each student to the assigned supervisor

SOFT SKILLS

Adobe CC, r statistic, STELLA, SPSS

PUBLICATION:

Elum, Ejiro and Salami, Abiodun Olusola. 'Bioremediation of a crude oil polluted soil with *Pleurotus pulmonarius* and *Glomus mosseae* using *Amaranthus hybridus* as a test plant' *Journal of Bioremediation and Biodegradation*. 1:113 (2010).